sygic.com 2014-05-18

# Sygic | Privacy policy

#### Scope

Sygic a.s. and affiliates (collectively “Sygic”, “us”, or “we”) appreciate the interest you (“You” or “Your”) have shown in our products and services by visiting our websites, [www.sygic.com](http://www.sygic.com/) or related communication channels such as PoliceTraps.com (collectively, the „Websites“). This Privacy Policy outlines our guidelines for the information Sygic collects when You interact with Sygic, such as when You visit our Websites, when You use the products and services offered by Sygic, when You subscribe to our newsletter or when You contact our Customer Support.

“ **Personal Information** ” is information about You that is personally identifiable to You like Your name, address, e-mail address, or phone number.

“ **Anonymous Information** ” means information that is not associated with or linked to Your Personal Information. Anonymous Information does not permit identification of You. Anonymous Information, such as basic usage statistics regarding Your use of the products and services offered by Sygic, does not by itself identify You to Sygic, though such information may be unique or consist of or contain information that You consider personal.

In accessing the Websites You accept all the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. You also agree that Sygic may amend and/or revise this Privacy Policy at its discretion, and You agree to be bound by these revisions and amendments. Your Personal Information may be processed in the country where it was collected as well as in other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in Your country.

If You do not agree with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy we request that You immediately cease using and accessing the Websites as well as the products and services for which You need to provide Personal Information.

#### Collection of Information by Sygic

The Personal Information we gather from You helps us learn about our visitors and customers. We use this information to provide You with our products and services and the products and services of our carefully selected partners, to develop new products and services, to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services, and to offer You additional information and opportunities.

We collect Personal Information that You submit to us voluntarily through our Websites and Your use of our products and services. We may collect Anonymous Information passively or actively. The types of Personal Information and Anonymous Information we collect are:

  * If You set up a “My Account” account, we will collect Your contact details such as email address and country, as well as, if appreciated, the information You provide us with in order to receive the newsletter of Your preference.

  * If You buy products or services from our web store, we will collect Your full name, the name of Your company (if applicable), Your postal address, e-mail, phone number. The online payment is processed by RBS WorldPay system, which is the payment processing business of The Royal Bank of Scotland Group, one of the largest banks in the world and a leading global brand. To guarantee the security of your payments, Sygic has chosen to use the biggest banking partners, as well as a secure, encrypted connection (SSL) technology. The name BIBIT B.V. may appear on your bank account statement. Please note that if the security department suspects fraud, we have the right to cancel the transaction for security reasons. The information we need to process Your payment of the purchase amount such as a bank account number or a credit card number is not among the information we collect.

  * If You request customer support services for Sygic products and/or services, we will collect Personal Information to enable us to provide customer support services to You, including Your name, email address, etc. We will also collect other information about the Sygic products You own, such as the serial numbers, date of purchase and information related to a support or service issue, some of which might include Personal Information.

  * By using a bulletin board or a chat room at our Websites, You should be aware that You are sharing all information You post on such bulletin boards or chat rooms with other users, including any Personal Information that You may choose to share, which shall become public information. Please choose the information that You share carefully. Sygic has no control over and is not responsible for anyone’s use, misuse, collection or disclosure of information You provide on a bulletin board or in a chat room by any third party. The information presented on bulletin boards and in chat rooms reflects the views of the individual users.

  * By joining a Sygic community, like Policetraps.com , Sygic will collect Personal Information like Your email address and any such information You will voluntarily provide to Sygic like map corrections or police traps report etc. This Personal Information is used for the purpose for which You provide it to Sygic.

  * Your user account name may be displayed throughout our Websites (and so available to the public) and is connected to all of Your Sygic activity. Other people can see Your posts, uploads, feedback, ratings and associated comments. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and policy violations on our Websites refer to user accounts and specific items. If You associate Your name with Your user account, the people to whom You have revealed Your name will be able to identify Your Sygic activities.

  * You may also be asked to provide Personal Information about a person other than Yourself (for example if You want to purchase a gift for someone and this Personal Information is required for the fulfilment of the delivery of Your purchase), such as name, address, email address. This Personal Information is used only for the purpose for which You provide it to Sygic.

  * Sygic may collect Personal Information through surveys for market research purposes to gain a better understanding of our customers, to improve our products and services, and to develop new products and services. The information we collect in such instances depends on the survey, but might include Your name, address, age, information about Your use of our services and products and the like.

  * If You subscribe to Sygic location-based services like Polictraps.com, Sygic may collect location data from Your device in order to provide You with the services requested.

  * If You send us an email to apply for a position with Sygic, we will collect Your email address and the full content of Your email, included attached files, such as resumes, and other information necessary to process Your application.

You represent, warrant and covenant that any Personal Information that You supply to Sygic is true, complete and accurate in all respects. You agree to notify Sygic immediately of any changes to Your Personal Information via our Websites.

#### Cookie Policy

Our Websites use Cookies to allow Sygic to collect data about the visitors of the Websites and users of our service (that we may associate with Personal Information that we have collected from You) and to customise and personalise our Websites for its viewers. A “Cookie” is a small text file that is placed on Your hard disk by a web server and is used by our Websites to identify Your computer whenever You visit our Websites. Sygic uses Cookies to store Your preferences and other related information. Sygic does not use Cookies to gather other information from Your personal computer. Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. If You choose to disable Cookies, some areas of the Websites may not work properly.

#### Information Collected Via Technology

As You navigate our Websites, certain Anonymous Information may also be collected passively, including Your Internet protocol address, browser type, and operating system. We also use Cookies and data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of Your visit and the information for which You searched and viewed. We use this Anonymous Information to measure the traffic on our Websites and to help us make our Websites more useful. We delete this information after a period of time.

Sygic may gather Anonymous Information from Your Sygic device when You are using it or when You are connecting it to a computer by using Sygic HOME. This Anonymous Information includes location information (information about Your location), information on how long it took You to travel certain routes, traffic patterns and on any technical glitches You may have encountered. The nature of the Anonymous Information that Your Sygic device transmits to us will not enable us to trace it back to an identifiable person; provided, however, You may elect to permit us to associate such Anonymous Information with Personal Information we have collected from You to provide You with specific location-based services that are tailored to meet Your needs or interests, to improve our products and services or to enforce the agreements, terms and conditions related to our Websites, products and services.

#### Personal Information we receive from Other Sources

We may receive Personal Information about You from third parties that provide us with data from their databases. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from You for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

How does Sygic processes Personal Information and Anonymous Information?

  * Personal Information will be collected, processed, and used by Sygic for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

  * Your Personal Information is used by Sygic to perform its obligations resulting from the delivery of the Sygic products and/or services to You, under the End-User License Agreement, Limited Warranty, if any, or any other terms that may apply. Sygic uses Your Personal Information to respond to Your questions and to fulfil Your requests or to manage interactive customer programmes. Sygic is entitled to contract third parties for its fulfilment of its obligations hereunder, however, Sygic will not provide Your Personal Information to a third party without Your permission, except as necessary to process Your order, fulfil Your requests or manage the interactive customer programmes or if compelled by law. These third parties may help Sygic to i.e. process information, fulfil customer orders, deliver products to You, manage and enhance customer data, provide customer service, assess Your interest in our products and services or to conduct customer research or satisfaction surveys. These third parties are obligated to protect Your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Sygic is and will remain responsible for the use of Your Personal Information.

  * Sygic uses Personal Information to contact You via mail, via email or phone to inform You of our (new) products and/or services, promotions we may offer, to submit a customer survey and any other marketing activity. Sygic is entitled to contract third parties to perform its direct marketing activities. Sygic may use Your Personal Information to conduct market research, to improve our products and/or services, to provide more responsive customer service and to improve our Websites and related Communication Channels, products and services.

  * Sygic also uses Personal Information to contact You, always on an “opt-in” basis, via mail, email address or phone to inform You of product and services of our carefully selected partners.

  * Sygic may provide, distribute or disclose Your Personal Information to third parties where Sygic reasonably believes that it is required to do so to conform to legal requirements or litigation, to protect and defend the rights or property of Sygic or other third parties, to enforce this Privacy Policy or act to protect the interests of its users. Sygic is also entitled to disclose Your Personal Information for the purposes of national security or other issues of public importance.

  * Your Personal Information and Anonymous Information are stored by Sygic in a central database. This central database is used by Sygic on a “need to know” basis in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

  * Sygic is entitled to exchange any Personal Information between the Sygic companies including those based in countries within and outside the EU, for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

  * Sygic may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as Your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to You. We may use this Anonymous Information to analyse usage patterns, to improve all our services, to develop new services and reserve the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information to third parties in its discretion.

  * We may also use Personal Information to resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems or to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our terms and conditions.

  * If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations for Your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Our disclosure of Your information

We may disclose Personal Information to respond to legal requirements, to enforce our policies, to respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or to protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. Such Personal Information will be disclosed in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

#### We may also share Your Personal Information with:

  * Members of Sygic’s trusted complainant programme when we in our sole discretion believe such disclosure is reasonably necessary or appropriate in connection with an intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, email address and company name.

  * Law enforcement or other governmental officials, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity. In such events, we will disclose information relevant to the investigation, such as name, city, state, zip code, telephone number, email address, user account history and IP address.

  * Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect Your privacy and our ability to keep the community free from bad actors, we will not otherwise disclose Your Personal Information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without an official request, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of Personal Information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

Please note that if You access our Websites from a shared computer or a public computer, such as one in an internet café, certain information about You, such as Your user account, may be visible to other individuals who use the computer after You.

#### Your Choices regarding Your Personal Information

We offer You choices regarding the collection, use and sharing of Your Personal Information. When You receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, You may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and You have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail You receive or by contacting us directly at [privacy@sygic.com](mailto:privacy@sygic.com) . However, regardless of Your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send You service e-mails regarding our products and services or notices of any updates to the terms and conditions or Privacy Policy. You may change any of the Personal Information in Your account by editing Your account information.

#### Accessing, reviewing and changing Your Personal Information

You can see, review and change much of Your Personal Information by signing in to Your Sygic account. Generally, we will not modify Your Personal Information because it is very difficult to verify Your identity remotely (e.g. via telephone). You must promptly update Your Personal Information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once You make a public posting, You may not be able to change or remove it. Upon Your request ([privacy@sygic.com](mailto:privacy@sygic.com) ), we will close Your account and remove Your Personal Information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on Your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We do retain Personal Information from closed accounts to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our terms and conditions, and take other actions permitted by law.

#### Transfer of Business Assets

In the event that Sygic undergoes a change of control or is sold or transferred, or in the event that substantially all of its assets are sold or transferred to a third party, Sygic’s website, products and services, and any personally identifiable information collected by Sygic, will be among the transferred assets. By using our Websites, products and/or services, You hereby agree and consent to such transfer or assignment of Your Personal Information collected by Sygic or to a change of control of Sygic, and You further waive any claims that could be made against us in relation thereto.

#### Feedback

If You provide feedback to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate this feedback with Your Personal Information. Sygic will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the Personal Information in the communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### Other Sites

Our provision of links to other Websites or locations is for Your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of these other Websites, location or its contents. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these third party Websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside Websites.

#### Children

We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of 16. If You believe that we have collected Personal Information about a visitor who is under the age of 16, please contact Us at [privacy@sygic.com](mailto:privacy@sygic.com), and such Personal Information will be deleted.

#### Safeguarding the information You share with us

We recognize our responsibility to protect the Personal Information You entrust to us. We take precautions including administrative, technical and physical measures to safeguard Your Personal Information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. However We cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information and Sygic cannot be held liable for any unauthorised access or use of the data You have supplied to Us You can also take precautions to protect Your Personal Information when You are on the Internet. Change Your passwords often using a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure You use a secure Internet browser.

#### Privacy questions

If You think that the use of Your Personal Information is not in alignment with the purpose for which You have provided it to Us, as described in this Privacy Policy, or if You have any questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact Us at [privacy@sygic.com](mailto:privacy@sygic.com). We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of 16. If You believe that we have collected Personal Information about a visitor who is under the age of 16, please contact us at [privacy@sygic.com](mailto:privacy@sygic.com).

#### Privacy Policy Updates

This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any substantial changes in the way we use Your Personal Information, we will post a notice on this page. If You object to any such changes, You must cease using our Websites and our products and services where Personal Information is collected. Continued use of our Websites and our products and services following notice of any such changes will indicate Your acknowledgement of the changes and agreement to be bound by the new terms and conditions.

Copyright © 2012 Sygic a.s. All rights reserved.
